<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installing Training resources on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/</link><description>Recent content in Installing Training resources on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Training Resources</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_00/</guid><description>Installing Training resources This will install resources that you will need for the configuration of AIManager in the next chapter.
Those are assets that typically already exist at a customer:
OpenLDAP AWX (Open Source Ansible Tower) with preloaded Playbooks RobotShop Demo App Demo Service Account This will also load training data for:
Log Anomalies
You will integrate with your live ELK instance but you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have 2-3 days to wait for ELK to collect enough logs.</description></item><item><title>Installing Training Resources</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_01/</guid><description>Installing Training resources This creates a Job in the default Namespace that will create and load all the stuff that you need for the next chapter. Run the following code to start the creation of the Training Resources.
cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF | oc apply -f - kind: ClusterRoleBinding apiVersion: rbac.authorization.k8s.io/v1 metadata: name: installer-default-default roleRef: apiGroup: rbac.authorization.k8s.io kind: ClusterRole name: cluster-admin subjects: - kind: ServiceAccount name: default namespace: default --- apiVersion: batch/v1 kind: Job metadata: name: waiops-easy-install-aimanager-practicum namespace: default spec: serviceAccountName: installer-default-default template: spec: containers: - name: install image: niklaushirt/cp4waiops-tools:1.</description></item><item><title>Check Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_02/</guid><description>Check if all Training Resources have been installed and are are ready This takes up to 20 minutes
This takes some time depending on what region of ROKS you have chosen.
❗ Wait for the installation to complete before continuing. The next step explains how to follow the installation progress. You can follow along the process by running:
./tools/11_fzth/stream_remote_logs.sh Or through the OpensHift Web Console:
Select default Namespace
Select Pods</description></item></channel></rss>