<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome to the IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Installation Training on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to the IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Installation Training on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_00/</guid><description>Introduction In this Training you will learn how to install IBM CloudPak for AIOps and how to configure some basic functionalities. The idea is to provide you with an optimised way to learn how to do a basic setup of CP4WAIOPS.
You will learn about the following topics: Installing AIManager from scratch Integrate AIManager with OpenLDAP for user management Integrate AIManager with ELK for Log Anomalies Define and train AI Models for Log Anomaly Detectiom Metric Anomaly Detection Event Grouping Similar Incidents Change Risk Create Policies for Story creation and Runbook assignment Integrate AIManager with Ansible Tower and create Runbooks in AIManager Create a RobotShop Application Topology Integrate AIManager with Slack (optional) Integrate AIManager with Service Now (optional) and those are the Topics that you are going to work on during this Training: Prerequisites In this chapter you will provision your OpenShift Cluster for the training.</description></item><item><title>Course Nomenclature</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_01/</guid><description>Example course page Navigation You can advance with the blue Next Button on the top right/bottom right.
Course Elements You will find the following elements in the course:
📥 Step Step: Task This is an example Step This is a step that you have to perform to advance in the course.
This is not part of the actual installation of AIManager and the commands are not hidden. So you just have to follow the instructions of the Task.</description></item><item><title>Basic Architecture</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_02/</guid><description>Basic Architecture The environement (Kubernetes, Applications, &amp;hellip;) create logs that are being fed into a Log Management Tool (ELK in this case).
External Systems generate Alerts and send them into the AIManager for Event Grouping. At the same time AIManager ingests the raw logs coming from the Log Management Tool (ELK) and looks for anomalies in the stream based on the trained model. It also ingests Metric Data and looks for anomalies If it finds an anomaly (logs and/or metrics) it forwards it to the Event Grouping as well.</description></item><item><title>Training Architecture</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/introduction/intro_03/</guid><description> Optimized Training Architecture For the this specific Demo environment:
ELK is installed for you to kearn how to integrate it For Log Anomaly simulation we&amp;rsquo;ll beusing pre-canned logs for the anomaly detection (inception) For Metrics, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using pre-canned metric data for training and for the anomaly detection (inception) The Events will be created from pre-canned content that is injected into AIManager There are also pre-canned ServiceNow Incidents as we don’t do the live integration with SNOW for this training The Webpages that are reachable from the Events are static and hosted on my GitHub The same goes for ServiceNow Incident pages if you don’t integrate with live SNOW</description></item><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/prerequisites/prereq_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/prerequisites/prereq_00/</guid><description>Get your ROKS Cluster (IBMers and IBM Partners only) In this chapter you will provision your cluster for the training.</description></item><item><title>Get your Cluster</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/prerequisites/prereq_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/prerequisites/prereq_01/</guid><description>Get your ROKS Cluster (IBMers and IBM Partners only) Step: Reserve a ROKS Cluster Reserve a ROKS Cluster
IBMers and IBM Business Partners can get a temporary Cluster from Techzone (ususally valid for up to 8 days)
Create a cluster for Practice/Self Education if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an Opportunity Number
Select the maximum end date that fits your needs (you can extend the duration once after creation)
Fill-in the remaining fields</description></item><item><title>Important remarks</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/prerequisites/prereq_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/prerequisites/prereq_02/</guid><description>⚠️⚠️ Important remarks before you start ⚠️⚠️ Those are remarks regarding feedback and problem reports I got from the field.
Those scripts have been tested thoroughly on different environments and have proven to be VERY reliable.
If you think that you hit a problem:
Make sure that you have provisioned a cluster with 5 worker nodes with 16 CPU and 64 GB each (b3c.16x64 - it&amp;rsquo;s easy to select the wrong size).</description></item><item><title>Installing the Operator</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_00/</guid><description> Installing the Operator In this chapter you will prepare your Cluster for the installation of AIManager
Prepare your PC or Mac to run commands against your cluster Create the basic resources (Namespace) Create the IBM Operator Catalog Install the CP4WAIOPS Operator</description></item><item><title>Preparing to run commands</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_01/</guid><description>Preparing to run commands in your Terminal Task: Connect to your OpenShift Cluster Connect the terminal to your ROKS Openshift Cluster with the OpenShift Web Console. Solution Open your Openshift Web Console
Select Copy Login Command
Copy the oc login .. string
Open your terminal
Paste the oc login .. command from above
Clone the GitHub Repository into your directory of choice
git clone https://github.com/niklaushirt/cp4waiops-deployer.git Go to the deployer directory</description></item><item><title>Preparing Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_02/</guid><description>Preparing the Installation In order to install the AIManager Operator you first have to create the following resources:
Namespace OperatorGroup IBM Pull Secret (Entitlement) You can find details on how to do this in the Official documentation: https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Task: Create the Namespace Solution Create the namespace (project) Create a namespace called cp4waiops, by running the following command:
oc create namespace cp4waiops This creates the Namespace in which you will install AIManager</description></item><item><title>Install Catalog</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_03/</guid><description>Installing the IBM Catalog Task: Install the IBM Catalog Source Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Add the AI Manager catalog source to your OpenShift cluster. Solution Run the following command to create the CatalogSource.
cat &lt;&lt; EOF | oc apply -f - apiVersion: operators.coreos.com/v1alpha1 kind: CatalogSource metadata: name: ibm-operator-catalog namespace: openshift-marketplace spec: displayName: ibm-operator-catalog publisher: IBM Content sourceType: grpc image: icr.io/cpopen/ibm-operator-catalog:latest EOF Update the CatalogSource to always use the current image digest by running the following commands:</description></item><item><title>Install Operator</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_04/</guid><description>Installing the Operator Task: Install the Operator Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Next you have to install the AIManager Operator. Solution Run the following command:
cat &lt;&lt; EOF | oc apply -f - apiVersion: operators.coreos.com/v1alpha1 kind: Subscription metadata: name: ibm-aiops-orchestrator namespace: cp4waiops spec: channel: v3.5 installPlanApproval: Automatic name: ibm-aiops-orchestrator source: ibm-operator-catalog sourceNamespace: openshift-marketplace EOF This creates the Operator instance that will be looking for an Installation definition and start the installation if it exists (you’ll create this in one of the next steps).</description></item><item><title>Check Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_05/</guid><description>Check if the Operator is ready Task: Verify that the Operator is running Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Check that the Operator is running and that you can continue with the next chapter to install AIManager. Solution Either run the following: oc get csv -n cp4waiops And you should see TODO entries with Succeeded state
NAME DISPLAY VERSION REPLACES PHASE ibm-aiops-orchestrator.v3.5.1 IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps AIManager 3.5.1 Succeeded ibm-automation-core.v1.3.11 IBM Automation Foundation Core 1.</description></item><item><title>Install AIManager</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-ai-manager/install_aimanager_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-ai-manager/install_aimanager_00/</guid><description>Creating the AIManager Instance In this chapter you will install AIManager
Task: Create the AIManager Instance Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to create the AIManager instance.
To do this create an instance of the AI Manager custom resource called ibm-cp-watson-aiops.
Solution Run the following command to create an instance of AIManager.
cat &lt;&lt; EOF | oc apply -f - apiVersion: orchestrator.aiops.ibm.com/v1alpha1 kind: Installation metadata: name: ibm-cp-watson-aiops namespace: cp4waiops spec: imagePullSecret: ibm-entitlement-key license: accept: true pakModules: - name: aiopsFoundation enabled: true - name: applicationManager enabled: true - name: aiManager enabled: true - name: connection enabled: false size: small storageClass: ibmc-file-gold-gid storageClassLargeBlock: ibmc-block-gold EOF This creates the Installation instance that the Operator will pick up and start the installation.</description></item><item><title>Check Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-ai-manager/install_aimanager_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-ai-manager/install_aimanager_01/</guid><description>Check if the AIManager Installation is ready Task: Verify that the AIManager Installation is ready Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Check that AIManager is running and that you can continue with the next chapter to install the third-party systems that will support your training. Solution Check with the Command Line Run the following:
while :; do clear; echo "Checking..."; echo "Exit with Ctrl-C"; echo "---------------"; echo "Not Ready: $(oc get po -n cp4waiops | grep -v Completed | grep -v Error |grep -v '0/' |wc -l| tr -d ' ')"</description></item><item><title>Training Resources</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_00/</guid><description>Installing Training resources In this chapter you will install resources that are needed for the configuration of AIManager in the next chapter.
Those are assets that typically already exist at a customer:
OpenLDAP AWX (Open Source Ansible Tower) with preloaded Playbooks RobotShop Demo App Demo Service Account This will also load training data for:
Log Anomalies
You will integrate with your live ELK instance but you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have 2-3 days to wait for ELK to collect enough logs.</description></item><item><title>Installing Training Resources</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_01/</guid><description>Installing Training resources Step: Launch the script to create the training resources Run the following code to start the creation of the Training Resources.
cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF | oc apply -f - kind: ClusterRoleBinding apiVersion: rbac.authorization.k8s.io/v1 metadata: name: installer-default-default roleRef: apiGroup: rbac.authorization.k8s.io kind: ClusterRole name: cluster-admin subjects: - kind: ServiceAccount name: default namespace: default --- apiVersion: batch/v1 kind: Job metadata: name: waiops-easy-install-aimanager-practicum namespace: default spec: serviceAccountName: installer-default-default template: spec: containers: - name: install image: niklaushirt/cp4waiops-tools:1.</description></item><item><title>Check Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_02/</guid><description> Check the Training Resources Step: Check if all Training Resources have been installed and are ready You can follow along the process by running:
./tools/11_fzth/stream_remote_logs.sh Or through the OpensHift Web Console:
Select default Namespace
Select Pods
Click on the waiops-easy-install-aimanager-practicum-... Pod
Select Logs
✅ And when done you should get the following with failed=0.
PLAY RECAP ********************************************************************* localhost : ok=XXX changed=XXX unreachable=0 failed=0 skipped=XXX rescued=0 ignored=0 ***************************************************************************************************************************** ✅ DONE *****************************************************************************************************************************</description></item><item><title>Initialize ELK</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-training-resources/configure_training_03/</guid><description>Initial ELK Setup Step: Open ELK In your OpenShift Console click on the Applications Menu
Select Logging
Step: Initialize ELK Click Allow selected permissions
Input app* for the index pattern
Click Next Step
Select @timestamp for time filter
Click Create Index Pattern
Click on Discover
ELK is now configured. Verify that you have Logs coming in.
You are now done with the chapter on creating Training Resources
Please continue to the next chapter to learn how to Configure AIManager.</description></item><item><title>Configure AIManager</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_00/</guid><description> Configure AIManager In this chapter you will:
Integrate AIManager with OpenLDAP for user management Integrate AIManager with ELK for Log Anomalies Define and train AI Models for Log Anomaly Detectiom Metric Anomaly Detection Event Grouping Similar Incidents Change Risk Create Policies for Story creation and Runbook assignment Integrate AIManager with Ansible Tower and create Runbooks in AIManager Create a RobotShop Application Topology Integrate AIManager with Slack</description></item><item><title>Get the information</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_01/</guid><description> Get the configuration Information Task: Get the configuration Information This will provide you with all the information and details that you need to configure AIManager in this chapter.
Run the following command to save a list of all the information to the MY_CONFIGURATION.txt file.
You will need this information for the configuration of AIManager in this chapter. ./tools/11_fzth/get_configuration_info.sh &amp;gt; MY_CONFIGURATION.txt</description></item><item><title>First Login</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_03/</guid><description>Your first Login to AIManager Task: Open the DemoUI In your OpenShift Console click on the Applications Menu
Select CP4WAIOps Demo UI
Login with token P4ssw0rd!
Copy the Admin Password
Open AIManager
Task: Login to AIManager Select IBM provided credentials
Login with admin user and the password you copied in the step above
Welcome to AIManager</description></item><item><title>Configure LDAP</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_04/</guid><description>Configure LDAP integration In this section you will connect to the existing LDAP Server and create a user with Administrative rights:
Task: Create the LDAP Connection Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=authentication-configuring-ldap-connections Connect to the existing LDAP Server using the following parameters:
Server type: Custom Base DN: dc=ibm,dc=com Bind DN: cn=admin,dc=ibm,dc=com Bind DN password: P4ssw0rd! LDAP server URL: ldap://openldap.openldap:389 Group filter: (&amp;amp;(cn=%v)(objectclass=groupOfUniqueNames)) User filter: (&amp;amp;(uid=%v)(objectclass=Person)) &amp;lt;-- Thats the only value you should have to change Group ID map: *:cn User ID map: *:uid Group member ID map: groupOfUniqueNames:uniqueMember Solution Create LDAP provider In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Access Control</description></item><item><title>Configure ELK</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_05/</guid><description>Configure ELK Integration In this section you will create the integration with ELK.
Task: Create the ELK Integration Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=connections-elk Create the ELK Integration with the following parameters:
ELK service URL: from MY_CONFIGURATION.txt Kibana URL: from MY_CONFIGURATION.txt Authentication type: Token Token: from MY_CONFIGURATION.txt Filter: { &amp;#34;query&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;bool&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;must&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;term&amp;#34; : { &amp;#34;kubernetes.namespace_name&amp;#34; : &amp;#34;robot-shop&amp;#34; } } } } } TimeZone: set to your Timezone Kibana port: 443 Mapping: { &amp;#34;codec&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;elk&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;message_field&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;message&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;log_entity_types&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Configure Runbooks</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_06/</guid><description>Configure Runbooks In this section you will create the connection to Ansible Tower and create your first Runbook.
Task: Create the Ansible Tower Connection Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=connections-ansible Create the connection to Ansible Tower Solution In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Define/Data and tool connections
Click Add connection
Under Ansible Automation Controller, click on Add connection
Click Connect
🔎 Get the data from your configuration file MY_CONFIGURATION.txt - section 2.3 Configure Runbooks - Ansible Automation Controller</description></item><item><title>Configure Policies</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_07/</guid><description>Configure Policies In this section you will enable a Policy to create Stories and create a Policy to assign a Runbook to a Story.
Task: Enable Story creation Policy Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=policies-default-story-creation AIManager provides two preset/of the box story creation policies. For story creation to occur, you must enable one of these default policies, or create your own custom story creation policy. These policies are disabled by default. Solution In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/Automations</description></item><item><title>Configure Applications</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_08/</guid><description>Create RobotShop Application In this section you will connect to the existing Kubernetes Cluster and create an Applciation for RobotShop.
Task: Create Kubernetes Connection (Observer) Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=connections-kubernetes A Kubernetes connection provides data about workloads in a Kubernetes cluster and namespace that you choose.
It loads baseline topology data, such as information about pods, worker nodes, and containers, as well as status from Kubernetes. Create a Kubernetes connection to create a Topology for the internal RoboShop application.</description></item><item><title>Configure Certificates</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-ai-manager/configure_aimanager_09/</guid><description> Create valid Ingress Certificates A signed certificate is needed on the NGNIX pods for the Slack and Teams integrations.
The AutomationUIConfig instance controls the certificates and the NGINX pods that use them.
Task: Create valid Ingress Certificates Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Create valid Ingress Certificates Solution Patch NetworkPolicy Run the following command to patch the NetworkPolicy
export WAIOPS_NAMESPACE=$(oc get po -A|grep aiops-orchestrator-controller |awk '{print$1}') cat &lt;</description></item><item><title>Train the Models</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_00/</guid><description> Train the Models In this chapter you will define and train AI Models for
Log Anomaly Detectiom Metric Anomaly Detection Event Grouping Similar Incidents Change Risk</description></item><item><title>Log Anomalies</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_01/</guid><description>Define and run LogAnomaly Training Task: Define and run LogAnomaly Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-natural-language-log-anomaly-detection In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to detect unusual patterns in your logs and notify you by generating an alert when they occur.
Set up and run training for Logs ingested from March 3rd 2022 to March 4th 2022
Solution Define Log Anomalies Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management</description></item><item><title>Metric Anomalies</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_02/</guid><description> Define and run Metric Anomaly Training Task: Define and run Metric Anomaly Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-metric-anomaly-detection In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to detect anomalous behaviour in your metrics and notify you by generating an alert when they occur. Solution Define Metric Anomalies Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management Under Metric anomaly detection, click on Set up training Click Next Click Next Click Done Run Metric Anomalies Training Click on the three dots in the upper right corner of the Metric anomaly detection card Select Start Training Status should say In progress And eventually say Deployed</description></item><item><title>Similar Incidents</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_03/</guid><description> Define and run Similar Incidents Training Task: Define and run Similar Incidents Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-similar-incidents In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to enable the discovery of historical incidents (tickets) to aid in the remediation of current incidents. Solution Define Similar Incidents Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management Under Similar Incidents, click on Set up training Click Next Click Next Click Done Run Similar Incidents Training Click on the three dots in the upper right corner of the Similar Incidents card Select Start Training Status should say In progress And eventually say Deployed</description></item><item><title>Change Risk</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_04/</guid><description> Define and run Change Risk Training Task: Define and run Change Risk Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-change-risk In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to determine how likely it is that a proposed change would cause a problem. Solution Define Change Risk Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management Under Change Risk, click on Set up training Click Next Click Next Under Deployment type check On completion Click Done Run Change Risk Training Click on the three dots in the upper right corner of the Change Risk card Select Start Training Status should say In progress And eventually say Deployed</description></item><item><title>Temporal Grouping</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_05/</guid><description>Define and run Temporal Grouping Training Task: Define and run Temporal Grouping Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-temporal-grouping This AI algorithm can start to discover groups after a pattern is learned, which might take hours or days. For example, if a problem occurs in the first and the fourth week of January and again in March, the algorithm learns to group the alerts that tend to co-occur when the problem happens.
In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to learn patterns in Event occurence and group patterns witt temporal correlation.</description></item><item><title>Check Training</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_06/</guid><description> Check Training Status Task: Check the Status of the Training Check your Training Cards. All should be green and say Deployed
You are now done with the chapter on Training the AIManager Models You have successfully completed installing and configuring AIManager ✅ Please continue to the next chapter to learn how to test your installation .</description></item><item><title>Test and Demo</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_00/</guid><description>Test and Demo In this chapter you will test and discover your installation.</description></item><item><title>Create Test Incident</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_01/</guid><description>Create a Test Incident Step: Create a Test Incident In your OpenShift Console click on the Applications Menu
Select CP4WAIOps Demo UI
Login with token P4ssw0rd!
Click on Create Incident Memory Leak
Wait for pop-up to go away and the Demo UI going back to the homepage</description></item><item><title>Examine the Incident</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_02/</guid><description>Examine the Incident Step: Examine the Alerts In the AIManager &amp;ldquo;Hamburger&amp;rdquo; Menu select Operate/Stories and Alerts
Click on Alerts
You should see some Alerts coming in
Step: Examine the Stories Click on Stories
You should see some Stories
Click on the first Story in the list (it should be P2 or P1 but the name can differ)
You should see some Stories
You should see the detail of the Story, with the Probable Cause, the Runbooks and the Similar Incidents</description></item><item><title>Clear the Incident</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/test-and-demo/test_and_demo_03/</guid><description>Clear the Incident Step: Clear the Incident Go back to the Demo UI
Click on Clear Stories and Events
Wait for pop-up to go away and the Demo UI going back to the homepage
The Alerts will be Closed and the Stories Resolved
You will have to wait for about 10 minutes for them to disappear (you can recreate the incident earlier, which will just re-open the existing Stories )</description></item><item><title>Slack Setup</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_01/</guid><description>Initial Slack Setup For the system to work you need to setup your own secure gateway and slack workspace. It is suggested that you do this within the public slack so that you can invite the customer to the experience as well. It also makes it easier for is to release this image to Business partners
You will need to create your own workspace to connect to your instance of CP4WAOps.</description></item><item><title>Create Workspace</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_02/</guid><description>Create your Slack Workspace Step: Create your Slack Workspace Create a Slack workspace by going to https://slack.com/get-started#/createnew and logging in with an email which is not your IBM email. Your IBM email is part of the IBM Slack enterprise account and you will not be able to create an independent Slack workspace outside if the IBM slack service.
After authentication, you will see the following screen:
Click Create a Workspace -&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Create Your App</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_03/</guid><description>Create Your Slack App Step: Create Your Slack App Create a Slack app, by going to https://api.slack.com/apps and clicking Create New App.
Select From an app manifest
Select the appropriate workspace that you have created before and click Next
Copy and paste the content of this file slack-app-manifest.yaml .
Adapt the Name and Display Name to your likings
Don&amp;rsquo;t bother with the URLs just yet, we will adapt them as needed.</description></item><item><title>Create Your Channels</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_04/</guid><description>Create Your Slack Channels Step: Create Your Slack Channels In Slack add a two new channels:
cp4waiops-stories cp4waiops-change-risk You can name the channel whatever you want.
Right click on each channel and select Copy Link
This should get you something like this https://xxxx.slack.com/archives/C021QOY16BW The last part of the URL is the channel ID (i.e. C021QOY16BW).
Write them down for both channels
Under Apps click Browse Apps
Select the App you just have created</description></item><item><title>Integrate</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_05/</guid><description>Integrate Your Slack App Step: Integrate Your Slack App - in Slack In the Basic Information menu get the Signing Secret (not the Client Secret!) and jot it down
In the OAuth &amp;amp; Permissions get the Bot User OAuth Token (not the User OAuth Token!) and jot it down
Step: Integrate Your Slack App - in AIManager Go to Data and tool connections
Under Slack select Add integration
Name it &amp;ldquo;Slack&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Get the Integration URL</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_06/</guid><description>Get the Integration URL (Public Cloud (ROKS, &amp;hellip;)) Step: Create the Integration URL In AIManager: Go to Data and tool connections
Under Slack click on 1 integration
Copy out the URL
This is the URL you will be using for step 6.</description></item><item><title>Configure</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_07/</guid><description>Create Slack App Communications Step: Event Subscriptions Return to the browser tab for the Slack app.
Select Event Subscriptions.
In the Enable Events section, click the slider to enable events.
For the Request URL field use the Request URL from step 5.
e.g: https://&amp;lt;my-url&amp;gt;/aiops/aimanager/instances/xxxxx/api/slack/events
After pasting the value in the field, a Verified message should display.
If you get an error please check that you have followed this Verify that on the Subscribe to bot events section you got:</description></item><item><title>Setup ServiceNow</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_01/</guid><description>Introduction The purpose of this guide is to provide a self-contained set of instructions to integrate with ServiceNow, summarizing instructions from IBM Documentation and other sources.
ServiceNow integrations provide historical and live data for change requests, incidents, and problems. ServiceNow integrations also provide inventory data for the ServiceNow observer.
You can only have one ServiceNow integration per instance. The instructions have been successfully tested against a ROKS cluster on the IBM Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_02/</guid><description>Prerequisites Step: Procure a ServiceNow Developer Instance Join the ServiceNow Developer Program , login with your credentials and request a Personal Developer Instance (PDI) with version &amp;ldquo;Paris&amp;rdquo; and patch 4 or higher. If you get a different version, you can release/return the instance you just got from the top right menu and request a new one. Then it will ask you to choose the version as shown below:
You can read about PDI here .</description></item><item><title>Configuring ServiceNow</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_03/</guid><description>Configuring ServiceNow You can create stories in IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps and issues in ServiceNow simultaneously. Both share information and can be tracked together. To ensure that this integration operates effectively, you must configure ServiceNow and ServiceNow integration in IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps.
After you configure ServiceNow and IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps, the updates that you make in IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps will flow into the Agent Workspace of ServiceNow.</description></item><item><title>Configuring AIManager</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_04/</guid><description>Configuring AIManager Now that we have created users and configured ServiceNow, we need to configure Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps to be able to integrate with ServiceNow.
Step: Creating ServiceNow integrations To create a ServiceNow integration, complete the following steps:
Log in to IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps.
From the console, click the navigation menu (four horizontal bars), then click Define &amp;gt; Data and tool integrations as shown below:</description></item><item><title>Testing Integration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_05/</guid><description>Testing the ServiceNow Integration Step: Creating stories as incidents in ServiceNow After the integration is finished, for every chatbot story created, an incident will be created in ServiceNow. For example, the creation of the following story number 9 in Slack:
This story has a corresponding incident created in ServiceNow. To access these incidents, from the ServiceNow home page search for agent, and click on Agent Workspace Home, as shown below</description></item><item><title>Custom Data</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_06/</guid><description> ServiceNow Custom Data Step: User 2 - abel.tuter Import the Changes from ./doc/servicenow/import_change.xlsx
Select Change - All from the right-hand menu Right Click on Numberin the header column Select Import Chose the ./doc/servicenow/import_change.xlsx file and click Upload Click on Preview Imported Data Click on Complete Import (if there are errors or warnings just ignore them and import anyway) Import the Incidents from ./doc/servicenow/import_incidents.xlsx
Select Incidents - All from the right-hand menu Proceed as for the Changes but for Incidents</description></item><item><title>General Troubleshooting</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/troubleshooting/troubleshooting_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/troubleshooting/troubleshooting_00/</guid><description>General Troubleshooting Official Troubleshooting Documentation The official IBM Troubleshooting Documentation is probably a safe place to start.
Check your installation Run the following tool:
./tools/11_check_install.sh This might give you some pointers as to why your instance is misbehaving.</description></item><item><title>Installation Problems</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/troubleshooting/troubleshooting_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/troubleshooting/troubleshooting_01/</guid><description>Installation Problems Topology Pods in Crashloop If the aiops-topology-xxx Pods are crashlooping, apply the following patches. I have only seen this happen on ROKS.
oc patch deployment aiops-topology-merge -n cp4waiops --patch-file &amp;#34;./ansible/roles/cp4waiops-ai-manager//templates/waiops/patches/aiops-topology-merge-patch.yaml&amp;#34; oc patch deployment aiops-topology-search -n cp4waiops --patch-file &amp;#34;./ansible/roles/cp4waiops-ai-manager//templates/waiops/patches/aiops-topology-search-patch.yaml&amp;#34; oc patch deployment aiops-topology-status -n cp4waiops --patch-file &amp;#34;./ansible/roles/cp4waiops-ai-manager//templates/waiops/patches/aiops-topology-status-patch.yaml&amp;#34; oc patch deployment aiops-topology-layout -n cp4waiops --patch-file &amp;#34;./ansible/roles/cp4waiops-ai-manager//templates/waiops/patches/aiops-topology-layout-patch.yaml&amp;#34; Pods with Pull Error If Pods are having pull errors, apply the following patches.</description></item><item><title>Integration Problems</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/troubleshooting/troubleshooting_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/troubleshooting/troubleshooting_02/</guid><description>Integration Problems Slack integration not working See here Check if data is flowing Check Log injection with Browser Go to DemoUI
Select tab System
Select Flink Connectors
Click on ELKInception3
You should see values go up under Records Sent when launching incident creation
Check Log injection with CommandLine To check if logs are being injected through the demo script:
Launch
./tools/22_monitor_kafka.sh Select option 5
You should see data coming in.</description></item></channel></rss>