<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Train the Models on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/</link><description>Recent content in Train the Models on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Train the Models</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_00/</guid><description> Train the Models In this chapter you will define and train AI Models for
Log Anomaly Detectiom Metric Anomaly Detection Event Grouping Similar Incidents Change Risk</description></item><item><title>Log Anomalies</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_01/</guid><description>Define and run LogAnomaly Training Task: Define and run LogAnomaly Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-natural-language-log-anomaly-detection In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to detect unusual patterns in your logs and notify you by generating an alert when they occur.
Set up and run training for Logs ingested from March 3rd 2022 to March 4th 2022
Need Help? Define Log Anomalies Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management</description></item><item><title>Metric Anomalies</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_02/</guid><description> Define and run Metric Anomaly Training Task: Define and run Metric Anomaly Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-metric-anomaly-detection In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to detect anomalous behaviour in your metrics and notify you by generating an alert when they occur. Need Help? Define Metric Anomalies Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management Under Metric anomaly detection, click on Set up training Click Next Click Next Click Done Run Metric Anomalies Training Click on the three dots in the upper right corner of the Metric anomaly detection card Select Start Training Status should say In progress And eventually say Deployed</description></item><item><title>Similar Incidents</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_03/</guid><description> Define and run Similar Incidents Training Task: Define and run Similar Incidents Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-similar-incidents In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to enable the discovery of historical incidents (tickets) to aid in the remediation of current incidents. Need Help? Define Similar Incidents Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management Under Similar Incidents, click on Set up training Click Next Click Next Click Done Run Similar Incidents Training Click on the three dots in the upper right corner of the Similar Incidents card Select Start Training Status should say In progress And eventually say Deployed</description></item><item><title>Change Risk</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_04/</guid><description> Define and run Change Risk Training Task: Define and run Change Risk Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-change-risk In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to determine how likely it is that a proposed change would cause a problem. Need Help? Define Change Risk Training In the AIManager “Hamburger” Menu select Operate/AI Model Management Under Change Risk, click on Set up training Click Next Click Next Under Deployment type check On completion Click Done Run Change Risk Training Click on the three dots in the upper right corner of the Change Risk card Select Start Training Status should say In progress And eventually say Deployed</description></item><item><title>Temporal Grouping</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_05/</guid><description>Define and run Temporal Grouping Training Task: Define and run Temporal Grouping Training Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=algorithms-temporal-grouping This AI algorithm can start to discover groups after a pattern is learned, which might take hours or days. For example, if a problem occurs in the first and the fourth week of January and again in March, the algorithm learns to group the alerts that tend to co-occur when the problem happens.
In this section you will set up and run training for this AI algorithm to learn patterns in Event occurence and group patterns witt temporal correlation.</description></item><item><title>Check Training</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/train-the-models/train_models_06/</guid><description> Check Training Status Task: Check the Status of the Training Check your Training Cards. All should be green and say Deployed
You are now done with the chapter on Training the AIManager Models You have successfully completed installing and configuring AIManager ✅ Please continue to the next chapter to learn how to test your installation .</description></item></channel></rss>