<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configure ServiceNow (optional) on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/</link><description>Recent content in Configure ServiceNow (optional) on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup ServiceNow</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_01/</guid><description>Introduction The purpose of this guide is to provide a self-contained set of instructions to integrate with ServiceNow, summarizing instructions from IBM Documentation and other sources.
ServiceNow integrations provide historical and live data for change requests, incidents, and problems. ServiceNow integrations also provide inventory data for the ServiceNow observer.
You can only have one ServiceNow integration per instance. The instructions have been successfully tested against a ROKS cluster on the IBM Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_02/</guid><description>Prerequisites Step: Procure a ServiceNow Developer Instance Join the ServiceNow Developer Program , login with your credentials and request a Personal Developer Instance (PDI) with version &amp;ldquo;Paris&amp;rdquo; and patch 4 or higher. If you get a different version, you can release/return the instance you just got from the top right menu and request a new one. Then it will ask you to choose the version as shown below:
You can read about PDI here .</description></item><item><title>Configuring ServiceNow</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_03/</guid><description>Configuring ServiceNow You can create stories in IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps and issues in ServiceNow simultaneously. Both share information and can be tracked together. To ensure that this integration operates effectively, you must configure ServiceNow and ServiceNow integration in IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps.
After you configure ServiceNow and IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps, the updates that you make in IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps will flow into the Agent Workspace of ServiceNow.</description></item><item><title>Configuring AIManager</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_04/</guid><description>Configuring AIManager Now that we have created users and configured ServiceNow, we need to configure Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps to be able to integrate with ServiceNow.
Step: Creating ServiceNow integrations To create a ServiceNow integration, complete the following steps:
Log in to IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps.
From the console, click the navigation menu (four horizontal bars), then click Define &amp;gt; Data and tool integrations as shown below:</description></item><item><title>Testing Integration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_05/</guid><description>Testing the ServiceNow Integration Step: Creating stories as incidents in ServiceNow After the integration is finished, for every chatbot story created, an incident will be created in ServiceNow. For example, the creation of the following story number 9 in Slack:
This story has a corresponding incident created in ServiceNow. To access these incidents, from the ServiceNow home page search for agent, and click on Agent Workspace Home, as shown below</description></item><item><title>Custom Data</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-servicenow/configure_snow_06/</guid><description> ServiceNow Custom Data Step: User 2 - abel.tuter Import the Changes from ./doc/servicenow/import_change.xlsx
Select Change - All from the right-hand menu Right Click on Numberin the header column Select Import Chose the ./doc/servicenow/import_change.xlsx file and click Upload Click on Preview Imported Data Click on Complete Import (if there are errors or warnings just ignore them and import anyway) Import the Incidents from ./doc/servicenow/import_incidents.xlsx
Select Incidents - All from the right-hand menu Proceed as for the Changes but for Incidents You are now done with the chapter on Configuring Service Now</description></item></channel></rss>