<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configure Slack (optional) on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/</link><description>Recent content in Configure Slack (optional) on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slack Setup</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_01/</guid><description>Initial Slack Setup For the system to work you need to setup your own secure gateway and slack workspace. It is suggested that you do this within the public slack so that you can invite the customer to the experience as well. It also makes it easier for is to release this image to Business partners
You will need to create your own workspace to connect to your instance of CP4WAOps.</description></item><item><title>Create Workspace</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_02/</guid><description>Create your Slack Workspace Create a Slack workspace by going to https://slack.com/get-started#/createnew and logging in with an email which is not your IBM email. Your IBM email is part of the IBM Slack enterprise account and you will not be able to create an independent Slack workspace outside if the IBM slack service.
After authentication, you will see the following screen:
Click Create a Workspace -&amp;gt;
Name your Slack workspace</description></item><item><title>Create Your App</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_03/</guid><description>Create Your Slack App Create a Slack app, by going to https://api.slack.com/apps and clicking Create New App.
Select From an app manifest
Select the appropriate workspace that you have created before and click Next
Copy and paste the content of this file slack-app-manifest.yaml.
Adapt the Name and Display Name to your likings
Don&amp;rsquo;t bother with the URLs just yet, we will adapt them as needed. Click Next
Click Create</description></item><item><title>Create Your Channels</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_04/</guid><description>Create Your Slack Channels In Slack add a two new channels:
cp4waiops-stories cp4waiops-change-risk You can name the channel whatever you want. Right click on each channel and select Copy Link
This should get you something like this https://xxxx.slack.com/archives/C021QOY16BW The last part of the URL is the channel ID (i.e. C021QOY16BW).
Write them down for both channels Under Apps click Browse Apps
Select the App you just have created
Invite the Application to each of the two channels by typing</description></item><item><title>Integrate</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_05/</guid><description>Integrate Your Slack App In the Slack App: In the Basic Information menu get the Signing Secret (not the Client Secret!) and jot it down
In the OAuth &amp;amp; Permissions get the Bot User OAuth Token (not the User OAuth Token!) and jot it down
In AIManager: Go to Data and tool connections
Under Slack select Add integration
Name it &amp;ldquo;Slack&amp;rdquo;
Paste the Signing Secret from above
Paste the Bot User OAuth Token from above</description></item><item><title>Get the Integration URL</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_06/</guid><description>Get the Integration URL (Public Cloud (ROKS, &amp;hellip;)) Create the Integration URL In AIManager: Go to Data and tool connections
Under Slack click on 1 integration
Copy out the URL
This is the URL you will be using for step 6.</description></item><item><title>Configure</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/configure-slack/configure_slack_07/</guid><description>Create Slack App Communications Return to the browser tab for the Slack app.
Event Subscriptions Select Event Subscriptions.
In the Enable Events section, click the slider to enable events.
For the Request URL field use the Request URL from step 5.
e.g: https://&amp;lt;my-url&amp;gt;/aiops/aimanager/instances/xxxxx/api/slack/events
After pasting the value in the field, a Verified message should display.
If you get an error please check that you have followed this
Verify that on the Subscribe to bot events section you got:</description></item></channel></rss>