<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installing the Operator on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/</link><description>Recent content in Installing the Operator on IBM CloudPak for Watson AIOps Training - Installation and Configuration</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing the Operator</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_00/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_00/</guid><description> Installing the Operator In this chapter you will prepare your Cluster for the installation of AIManager
Prepare your PC or Mac to run commands against your cluster Create the basic resources (Namespace) Create the IBM Operator Catalog Install the CP4WAIOPS Operator</description></item><item><title>Preparing to run commands</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_01/</guid><description>Preparing to run commands in your Terminal Task: Connect to your OpenShift Cluster Connect the terminal to your ROKS Openshift Cluster with the OpenShift Web Console. Solution Open your Openshift Web Console
Select Copy Login Command
Copy the oc login .. string
Open your terminal
Paste the oc login .. command from above
Clone the GitHub Repository into your directory of choice
git clone https://github.com/niklaushirt/cp4waiops-deployer.git Go to the deployer directory</description></item><item><title>Preparing Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_02/</guid><description>Preparing the Installation In order to install the AIManager Operator you first have to create the following resources:
Namespace OperatorGroup IBM Pull Secret (Entitlement) You can find details on how to do this in the Official documentation: https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Task: Create the Namespace Solution Create the namespace (project) Create a namespace called cp4waiops, by running the following command:
oc create namespace cp4waiops This creates the Namespace in which you will install AIManager</description></item><item><title>Install Catalog</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_03/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_03/</guid><description>Installing the IBM Catalog Task: Install the IBM Catalog Source Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Add the AI Manager catalog source to your OpenShift cluster. Solution Run the following command to create the CatalogSource.
cat &lt;&lt; EOF | oc apply -f - apiVersion: operators.coreos.com/v1alpha1 kind: CatalogSource metadata: name: ibm-operator-catalog namespace: openshift-marketplace spec: displayName: ibm-operator-catalog publisher: IBM Content sourceType: grpc image: icr.io/cpopen/ibm-operator-catalog:latest EOF Update the CatalogSource to always use the current image digest by running the following commands:</description></item><item><title>Install Operator</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_04/</guid><description>Installing the Operator Task: Install the Operator Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Next you have to install the AIManager Operator. Solution Run the following command:
cat &lt;&lt; EOF | oc apply -f - apiVersion: operators.coreos.com/v1alpha1 kind: Subscription metadata: name: ibm-aiops-orchestrator namespace: cp4waiops spec: channel: v3.5 installPlanApproval: Automatic name: ibm-aiops-orchestrator source: ibm-operator-catalog sourceNamespace: openshift-marketplace EOF This creates the Operator instance that will be looking for an Installation definition and start the installation if it exists (you’ll create this in one of the next steps).</description></item><item><title>Check Installation</title><link>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_05/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:57:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://niklaushirt.github.io/cp4waiops-training/installing-operator/install_operator_05/</guid><description>Check if the Operator is ready Task: Verify that the Operator is running Documentation https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/cloud-paks/cloud-pak-watson-aiops/3.5.0?topic=manager-starter-installation-cli Check that the Operator is running and that you can continue with the next chapter to install AIManager. Solution Either run the following: oc get csv -n cp4waiops And you should see TODO entries with Succeeded state
NAME DISPLAY VERSION REPLACES PHASE ibm-aiops-orchestrator.v3.5.1 IBM Cloud Pak for Watson AIOps AIManager 3.5.1 Succeeded ibm-automation-core.v1.3.11 IBM Automation Foundation Core 1.</description></item></channel></rss>